Louis A. Witzeman Collection of Rural/Metro Corporation Records, 1947-2004
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series 5: Photographs, 1948-1993
  - Subseries: Fire Stations. 1950-1975
    - Unidentified. undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified. 1965-1970 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - West Side Headquarters. 1965-1975 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Woodmeade. undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Subseries: Fires. 1948-1990
    - Brush and Hay (Identified). undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Brush and Hay (Identified). 1964-1974 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Brush and Hay (Unidentified). undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Brush and Hay (Unidentified). 1963-1978 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Commercial Property (Identified). undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Commercial Property (Identified). 1950-1975 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Commercial Property (Identified). 1978 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Commercial Property (Identified). 1990 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Commercial Property (Unidentified) (1 of 3). undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Commercial Property (Unidentified. undated (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    - Commercial Property (Unidentified). 1965-1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Residential Property (Identified). undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Residential Property (Identified). 1948-1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Residential Property (Unidentified). undated (Box 16, Folder 6-10)
    - Residential Property (Unidentified). 1967-1970 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Vehicle (Identified). 1960-1970 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Vehicle (Unidentified). undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Vehicle (Unidentified). 1968 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Subseries: Miscellaneous. undated
    - Miscellaneous. undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Subseries: Publicity. 1950-1993
    - Captioned. undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Captioned. 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Dispatchers. undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - General. undated (Box 17, Folder 6-8)
    - General. 1971 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Robertson, Fire Chief. undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Robertson, Fire Chief. 1966 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Scottsdale Station Groundbreaking. undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Training Exercises. undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Training Exercises. 1950 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Witzeman, Louis A. undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Witzeman, Louis A. 1969-1993 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Series 6: Negatives and Slides. 1950-1982
  1.5 linear feet (Approximately 2,250 items)
  This series includes negatives and slides of equipment, fire engines, fire hazards, fire stations, fires (brush and hay, commercial and residential property, vehicular), and Rural/Metro publicity. Additionally, there are microfilm slides of both maps and aerial views of Scottsdale, Arizona—in the 1970s these microfilm slides were used in microfilm readers (placed in fire engine cabs) to determine the locations of fires and other emergencies.
  - Negatives: Equipment; Pumps and Hoses. undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Negatives: Equipment; Rescue Equipment. undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Central Yavapai F.D. undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Folsom F.D. undated (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Hermosillo F.D. undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Oracle F.D. undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; “Plain Janes.” undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Rural/Metro. undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Rural/Metro. 1966 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Negatives: Fire Engines; Show Low F.D. undated (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Negatives: Fire Hazards; General. undated (Box 17, Folder 27-28)
  - Negatives: Fire Stations; Scottsdale. undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Negatives: Fire Stations; Unidentified. undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Negatives: Fire Stations; Unidentified. 1952-1969 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Negatives: Fire Stations; West Side Headquarters. undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Negatives: Fires; Brush and Hay (Identified). 1952 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
  - Negatives: Fires; Commercial Property (Identified). undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Negatives: Fires; Commercial Property (Unidentified). undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Negatives: Fires; Residential Property (Identified). undated (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
  - Negatives: Fires; Residential Property (Unidentified). undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Negatives: Fires; Vehicle (Identified). undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Negatives: Fires; Vehicle (Unidentified). undated (Box 18, Folder 13-14)
  - Negatives: Publicity; General. undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Slides: Boats; Boston F.D. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Slides: Equipment; Communication Devices, Protective Clothing and Rescue Equipment. undated (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Slides: Equipment; Communication Devices, Protective Clothing and Rescue Equipment. 1969-1975 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Slides: Equipment; Hydrants, the “Snail,” and the “Water Tank.” 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Slides: Equipment; Microfilm Reader. 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Slides: Equipment; Pumps and Hoses. 1967-1969 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Slides: Equipment; Sprinkler Systems. 1969-1974 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Slides: Equipment; X-Hyd Opener. 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Cambridge, Massachusetts F.D. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Elmira Heights, New York F.D. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Fairview F.D. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Foam Truck. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Hamilton, Ontario F.D. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Massachusetts Port Authority. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Nogales F.D. 1971 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Norwood, Massachusetts F.D. 1972 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Phoenix F.D. 1973 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; “Plain Janes.” 1969-1974 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Rural/Metro. undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Rural/Metro. 1969-1975 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Scottsdale F.D. 1969-1975 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Sun City F.D. 1973-1976 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Tucson F.D. 1963 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Unidentified. 1969-1979 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Yakima, Washington F.D. “Squirt.” 1973 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Slides: Fire Engines; Yavapai F.D. 1966 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Slides: Fire Hazards; General. 1969-1974 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Apache Trail. undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Green Valley. 1969 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Litchfield Park. undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Litchfield Park. 1969 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Oracle. 1969 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Paradise Valley Locations. 1974 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Rochester, New York. 1972 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Scottsdale #10. undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Scottsdale #10. 1969-1979 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Scottsdale #11. 1971 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Scottsdale Main (Demolition Process). 1967-1974 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Sun City. 1975 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; Unidentified. 1969-1974 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; West Side Headquarters. undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Slides: Fire Stations; West Side Headquarters. 1970 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Slides: Fires; Commercial Property (Identified). 1969 (Box 19, Folder 19-20)
  - Slides: Fires; Commercial Property (Identified). 1972 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Slides: Fires; Commercial Property (Identified). 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Slides: Fires; Commercial Property (Identified). 1975 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Slides: Fires; Commercial Property (Unidentified). 1969-1976 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Slides: Fires; Forest (Unidentified). 1975 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Slides: Fires; Residential Property (Identified). 1969 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Slides: Fires; Residential Property (Identified). 1972 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Slides: Fires; Vehicle (Identified). 1974 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Slides: Fires; Vehicle (Identified). 1979 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Slides: Fires; Vehicle (Unidentified). 1969-1973 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Slides: Forestry; Helicopters, Slurry, and Tankers. 1974 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Aerial Views. 1973 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Casas Adobes. 1968 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Charts and Graphs. undated (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Charts and Graphs. 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Drinkwater’s Box Culverts. 1974 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; European Magazine Articles on Firefighting. 1974 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; House Damage. 1972 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Inspection Forms. 1973 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Los Arcos Framing. 1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Microfilm Maps. 1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Microfilm Maps. 1974 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Miscellaneous. 1970-1982 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Papago Plaza. 1969 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Paradise Valley Homes. 1972 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Plaza Del Sol. 1969 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Report to City of Scottsdale. 1979 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Scottsdale Buildings. 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Stanford Research Institute. 1976 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Sun City North Buildings. 1969 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Slides: Miscellaneous; Witzeman European Trip. 1970 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Slides: Publicity; General. undated (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Slides: Publicity; General. 1963-1975 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Slides: Publicity; Scottsdale Municipal Show and Tell Event. 1970 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Slides: Publicity; Training Exercises. undated (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Slides: Publicity; Training Exercises. 1968-1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
- Series 7: Scrapbooks. 1948-1986
  The Scrapbook Series contains photocopies of six scrapbooks. [Note: an additional (seventh) scrapbook is located in Series 11: Oversized Materials]. One scrapbook consists solely of photographs of the Thirtieth Anniversary Party. The other scrapbooks contain photographs and news clippings of a general nature concerning Rural/Metro.
  - Anniversary Party—30th. 1978 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - General. 1949-1956 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - General. 1951-1969 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - General. 1952-1963 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - General. 1970-1986 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - General. 1971-1979 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Series 8: News Clippings. 1948-2004
  The News Clippings Series contains photocopies of news articles relating to Rural/Metro history. While the bulk of the new clippings are general in nature, the series also contains clippings on the intensely-campaigned 2003 Scottsdale Election where Scottsdale citizens voted to retain the private fire protection services of Rural/Metro rather than switch to a municipally-run fire department.
  - General. undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - General. 1948 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - General. 1950-1959 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - General. 1963-1969 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - General. 1970-1971 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - General. 1972-1979 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - General. 1980-1985 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - General. 1986-1987 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - General. 1988-1989 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - General. 1992-1999 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - General. 2000-2004 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Scottsdale Election. 2002-2003 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Scottsdale Election. 2003 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
- Series 9: Audiovisual. 1969-2001
  1.0 linear foot (Approximately 225 items)
  The Audiovisual Series includes audiocassette tapes, reel audiotape, videocassettes tapes (VHS), Super 8 movie film, computer diskettes, and a slide/audiocassette tape presentation. Of note, the series contains audiotaped interviews with Rural/Metro founder Lou Witzeman, Rural/Metro attorney Lou Jekel, and other important figures in Rural/Metro history. Also, the series contains the March 7, 2000, Good Morning America television broadcast (in VHS format) concerning Rural/Metro and the Scottsdale Fire Sprinkler Ordinance.
  - Audiocassette Tapes; No Title. undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Audiocassette Tapes; Robertson Interview. 1996 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Audiocassette Tapes; Rural/Metro History (Lou Witzeman, Lou Jekel, Jim Stenger, Bob Oden, and Fred Roof). 1996 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Computer Diskettes; Miscellaneous. undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Reel Audiotapes; Sprinkler Systems Slide Show Soundtrack. undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Slide and Audiocassette Tape Presentation; Rural/Metro Fire Sprinkler Tests. 1982 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
  - Super 8 Movie; Experimental #21 Pump Lift Operation. 1969 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Good Morning America Broadcast—“Fire Sprinkler Ordinance.” March 7, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Rural/Metro 50th Anniversary and Music Video. 1998 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Rural/Metro Fire Department Banquet 2001. 2001 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Rural/Metro “Heroes.” 1996 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Rural/Metro Story. 1985 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Snail Tests at China Lake. 1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Vintage Rural/Metro. undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Videocassette Tapes (VHS); Witzeman Center for Privatization. undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Series 10: Memorabilia. 1976-1998
  .5 linear feet (Approximately 65 items)
  This series includes an identification card, a badge, business cards, buttons, decals, membership cards, a name tag, patches, a pen light, pins, and subscriber window signs. [Note: additional memorabilia are located in Series 11: Oversized Materials].
  - Arizona Security Guard Identification Card; Louis A. Witzeman. 1978 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Badge; Scottsdale Fire Department. undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Business Cards; Walter D. Stull. undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Business Cards; Louis A. Witzeman. undated (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Business Cards; Louis A. Witzeman. 1988 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Buttons; Miscellaneous. undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Decals; Miscellaneous. undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Decals; Thirtieth Anniversary. 1978 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Membership Cards; Louis A. Witzeman. 1976-1981 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Name Tag; Lou Witzeman Chairman of the Board of Rural/Metro Corporation. undated (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Patches; Miscellaneous. undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Pen Light; Rural/Metro. undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Pins; Fortieth Anniversary. 1988 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Pins; Miscellaneous. undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Playing Cards; Rural/Metro. undated (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Signs; Subscriber Window Signs. undated (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Series 11: Oversized Materials (contains memorabilia,photographs, and one scrapbook)
  .5 linear feet (Approximately 150 items)
  - Memorabilia: Decals; Fire Engine Door Decal. undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Fire Engines; Rural/Metro. undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Fires; Brush and Hay (Unidentified). undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Fires; Commercial Property (Identified). undated (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Fires; Residential Property (Unidentified). undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbooks: General. 1948-1952 (Box 26, Folder 6)